Catherine Viviano Gallery Records
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence, 1939-1985, Series 2:; (Boxes 3-6; 5.5 linear feet)
  - Correspondence with Museums, Galleries, and Art-Related Institutions Abroad, 1951-1975, 2.3:
    This subseries contains letters between Catherine Viviano and museum directors, gallery owners, curators, publishers, and individuals affiliated with arts organizations in Europe, Brazil, Canada, and Mexico. Included in the correspondence are loan forms, shipping receipts, bank slips, invoices, auction orders, insurance claims, press releases, and printed material. Correspondence concerns sales and appraisals; exhibition itineraries; and requests for biographical information.
    Among the artists frequently cited in the correspondence are: Afro Basaldella, Joseph Glasco, Peter Lanyon, Luciano Minguzzi, Bernard Perlin, Bernard Rosenthal, and Kay Sage. Correspondence with Galerie Gunter Franke and Max Beckmann Gesellschaft Archiv provides sales information and detailed exhibition histories for individual works of art by Beckmann.
    Files are arranged alphabetically by institution, and letters within the folder are in chronological order.
    - Antonio Souza Galeria,1956-1960, undated (Box 9, Folder 61)
    - Archivo Storio d'Arte Contemporania, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 62)
    - Art Gallery of Ontario, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 63)
    - Art Gallery of Toronto, 1955-1968 (Box 9, Folder 64)
    - Art International, 1958-1966 (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - Arthur Jeffress Gallery, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 66)
    - The Arts Council of Great Britain, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 67)
    - Badische Kunstverein, 1963, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 68-69)
    - Bayerischen Staatsgemäldesammlungen, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 70)
    - Bezalel National Museum, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 71)
    - The British Arts Council, 1961-1966 (Box 9, Folder 72)
    - Brussels Universal and International Exhibition, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 73)
    - Casa Fontana, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - Documenta II, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 75)
    - Ente Autonomo, La Biennale Di Venezia, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 76)
    - Frankfurter Kunstkabinett, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 77)
    - Galerie Anne Abels, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 78)
    - Galerie Craven, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 79)
    - Galerie d'art Moderne, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 80)
    - Galerie d'eendt nv, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 81)
    - Galerie de France, 1953-1956 (Box 9, Folder 82)
    - Galerie Elfriede Wirnitzer, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 83)
    - Galerie Gunther Franke, 1957-1976, undated, (7 folders) (Box 9, Folder 84-90)
    - Galerie im Erker, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 91)
    - Galerie Springer Berlin, 1957-1969, undated (Box 9, Folder 92)
    - Galerie Thomas, 1971-1975 (Box 9, Folder 93)
    - Galerie Wilheim Grosshenning, 1960-1975, (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 94-97)
    - Galleria D'Arte Del Naviglio, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 98)
    - Galleria Delle Carozze, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 99)
    - Galleria Nazionale D'Arte Moderna, 1960, undated (Box 9, Folder 100)
    - Gimpel Fils, 1955-1978 (Box 9, Folder 101)
    - Hamburger Kunsthalle, 1958-1968 (Box 9, Folder 102)
    - The Hanover Gallery, 1950-1953 (Box 9, Folder 103)
    - Herbert Meyer Ellinger Gallery, 1971-1975 (Box 9, Folder 104)
    - Institute of Contemporary Arts, undated (Box 9, Folder 105)
    - International Biennial Exhibition of Prints in Tokyo,1960 (Box 9, Folder 106)
    - Klipstein and Kornfeld,1960 (Box 9, Folder 107)
    - Kunst und Museumvein Wuppertal, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 108)
    - Kunsthalle Bremen, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 109)
    - Kunsthistorisches Institut, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 110)
    - L'Obelisco Galeria d' Arte, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 111)
    - La Loggia Galleria d'Arte, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 112)
    - The Leicester Galleries, 1957-1958 (Box 9, Folder 113)
    - Marlborough Fine Art Limited,1974 (Box 9, Folder 114)
    - Max Beckmann Gesellschaft Archiv, 1961-1969, undated, (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 115-118)
    - Montreal Museum of Art, 1960-1968 (Box 9, Folder 119)
    - Museu De Arte Moderna, Sao Paulo Biennial, 1953-1961, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 120-121)
    - National Galerie Berlin, 1966-1968, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 122)
    - National Gallery of Canada, 1968-1970 (Box 9, Folder 123)
    - Niedersächsische Landesgalerie,1964 (Box 9, Folder 124)
    - P. Accademia Dei Virtuosi Al Pantheon, 1967-1973 (Box 9, Folder 125)
    - Roman Norbert Ketterer, 1957-1972, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 126-128)
    - Societe Des Expositions, Du Palais Des Beaux-Arts, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 129)
    - Tate Gallery,1970 (Box 9, Folder 130)
    - University of London, Courtauld Institute of Art, 1951, undated (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - Winnipeg Art Gallery, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 132)
- Business Records, 1949-1972, Series 3:; (Boxes 10-11; 1.0 linear feet)
  This series documents Catherine Viviano's business transactions as a dealer and after the gallery closed, as a freelance art consultant. Files include ledgers, a notebook of sales and loose pages of sales, check registers, correspondence, notes, and scattered business and legal files.
  Ledgers record cash receipts, cash disbursements, accounts receivable, accounts payable, Catherine Viviano's personal expenses, sales by artists, and a general journal. Also found are a notebook and loose ledger pages of sales and payments to artists, including a list of the artwork sold at the gallery's first exhibition. Generally, the titles of artwork are omitted in the sales records.
  Included are Catherine Viviano's letters to the managing agent for the 42 East 57th Street building pertaining to the renewal of the lease and requests for routine repairs in the gallery. Miscellaneous business records contain shipping instructions and a receipt for delivery of artwork. Business records can also be found in artists' files, correspondence, and printed material.
  Legal files include a suit for non-payment of art brought by Catherine Viviano against a client and an affidavit with respect to character for Peter C. Salerno for his admission to the State Bar of New York.
  Ledgers and a notebook of sales of artwork to individuals were disbound by the processor. The records are arranged in chronological order.
  - Ledgers (Box 10)
    - Cash Receipts and Cash Disbursements; Accounts Receivable and Accounts Payable; Catherine Viviano's Personal Expenses; and Miscellaneous A, 1949-1956, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Sales to Individuals, A-Z and Scattered Payments to Artists, B-V,1950-1955 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Sales, By Artists, A-R; Cash Receipts; Cash Disbursements; and Accounts Receivable, 1958-1963 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - General and Administrative; Accounts Payable and Accounts Receivable; and General Journal, 1959-1964 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Cash Receipts, Cash Disbursements, Sales, and Personal Cash Disbursements, 1963-1972 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - General Ledger, Cash Receipts, and Cash Disbursements, 1965-1970 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Catherine Viviano Galleries, Inc., General Ledger and Genie Fastener, Inc.; and General Ledger, 1967-1969, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
    - Notebook relating to Sales of Artwork and Payments to Artists, 1952-1961 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Ledger Pages and Lists relating to the Sales of Artwork, First-Fourth Exhibitions at the Catherine Viviano Gallery, 1951-1959 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Check Registers, 1959-1961, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 12-14)
    - Check Registers, 1961-1971, (8 folders) (Box 11, Folder 1-8)
    - Correspondence relating to Catherine Viviano Gallery Space at 42 East 57th Street, New York, NY, 1960-1969 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Notes, 1956-1959, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Scattered Business Records, 1953, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Legal Records, 1961-1971, undated, (3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 12-14)
- Printed Material, 1930-1990, Series 4:; (Boxes 11-13; 1.6 linear feet)
  Printed material houses catalogues of solo and group shows, announcements, invitations, brochures of exhibitions held at the Catherine Viviano Gallery and other venues. Files also contain miscellaneous printed material: press releases, artist's statement, biographical matter, clipping, an art periodical, and a monograph.
  Included are catalogues of one-man shows for artists that Viviano represented over the years: Max Beckmann, Peter Lanyon, Joseph Glasco, Bernard Perlin, Dan Rice, Felix Ruvolo, Kay Sage, and Emilio Vedova. There is a 1973 catalogue of Max Beckmann's paintings, sculptures, drawings, and watercolors, which was organized by Catherine Viviano in her role as an independent dealer. Exhibition catalogs can also be found in Series 1: Artists' Files and Series 2: Correspondence.
  The materials within the folders are arranged chronologically.
  - Exhibition Catalogues (Catherine Viviano Gallery)1951-1973, (5 folders) (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
  - Exhibition Catalogues (other venues) 1930-1968, (8 folders) (Box 11, Folder 6-13)
  - Exhibition Catalogues (other venues), 1969-1990, undated, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 1-5)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Invitations, and Brochures (other venues), 1958-1979, undated, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 6-8)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1952-1979, undated, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 9-11)
  - Miscellaneous Monographs, 1948-1954, undated, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
- Photographs (1948-1954), undated, Series 5:; (Box 14; 1 folder)
  This series houses photographs of miscellaneous artwork used for art reference.
  Photographs can also be found in Series 1: Artists' Files and Series 2: Correspondence.
  - Photographs of Artwork (1948-1954), undated (Box 14, Folder 3)